Objective

I am a newly trained AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner built on 20+ years' experience applying my SME in EDW - Business Intelligence - Data Integration (ETL) that span across Manufacturing, Consulting, Healthcare and Entertainment sectors. With the goal of strict confidential data security compliance, such as HIPAA & SOX and pursuing real-time operational Data Analytics efficiency that will benefit significant savings by trading capital expenses (on-prem) vs variable expenses (pay-as-you-go) Cloud Computing platform.

Selected Accomplishments

- Leverage new innovative Bible translation method, MAST, empowering native mother tongue translators producing fast translation with accuracy, naturalness, culturally relevant Bibles ensuring high acceptance rate by the local churches. Project Management utilized open-source apps & platform securing translation data on the cloud. Published 5 Gateway Languages Open Source (ULB) Bible with supporting resources (Commentary, Questions, and Key Words) that reduced ~66% timeline from avg 5 years to 1.5 year, and operational budget savings of \$1,100,000, ~66% less cost than other GLs benchmark.
- Worked in conjunction with consulting firm and various vendors and successfully charter 5-year EDW
 EMPI Roadmap initiative for the regional hospital systems. This Meaningful Use single-version-of-truth
 platform consolidates patients & financial data from various EHR/EMR, legacy systems, social media,
 hand written docs, etc.. enabling real-time BI data analytics capability instead of spending days/months
 digging through silos of data repo for metrics reporting.

Employment History

Wycliffe Associates, Gateway Languages-Asia Reg Director, Orlando, FL/Singapore Nov 2017 – Sep 2020 KPMG LLP (Beacon Partners), Senior Associate, Advisory, San Francisco, CA Feb 2015 – Nov 2015 Caesars Entertainment, EDW - Data Architect, Las Vegas, NV May 2014 – Aug 2014 Memorial Health Systems, EDW/BI – Data Warehouse Engineer, Springfield, IL May 2011 – May 2014 Hewlett-Packard Corp, EDW/BI Engineer – Data Integration, Palo Alto, CA 2006 – 2010 Accenture, Sr. Informatica Consultant, Houston, TX 2005 - 2006 Hewlett-Packard Corp, BI – Supply Chain, Houston, TX 2000 - 2005 Albemarle Corp., Programmer Analyst, Houston, TX 1996 – 2000 Powell Electrical Mfg., Network Administrator, Houston, TX 1995 – 1996

Education

Computer Sciences B.A., University of Texas at Austin.

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner.

HealthCare IT Certificate Program

Kimball University - ETL Architecture in Depth

Kimball University - Dimensional Modeling in Depth

Oracle 11g: Program with PL/SQL

The Data Warehousing Institute (TDWI) – Data Model

The Data Warehousing Institute (TDWI) – Data Modeling and Dimensional Modeling Informatica Power Center 7 Level II Developer/Admin

<u>Keywords</u> ETL BI EDW HL7 Healthcare Entertainment Manufacturing Enterprise Data Warehouse Business Intelligence Data Management Analytics Integration Information Builders Omni-Patient EMPI Enterprise Master Patient Index, iWay Data Integration Data Quality Master Data Center EHR EMR Cerner Millennium CPSI AllScripts ERP Sapphire (SMS) Lawson DataBase MS-SQL server SSIS Oracle SQL*Plus Oracle SQL*Loader Teradata v13 Informatica Power Center HP NeoView, eDialog ExactTarget SalesForce Door43 BibleInEveryLanguage.org Github ULB translationStudio tS MAST Mobilized Assist Supporting Translation